# **MEGAN WONG**

San Mateo, CA | (415) 994-1567 | mwong068@gmail.com | Github: mwong068 | LinkedIn: mwong068 | Portfolio: megan-wong.com

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experience in Ruby on Rails and Javascript based programming and current Software Engineer Intern with a small startup in San Francisco. Former pastry chef who developed hundreds of products from scratch daily and employed adaptability in a fast-paced environment. 2+ years in project management and a knack for conceptualizing and delivering elegant, user-friendly solutions. Excited to connect people through technology after many years of connecting people through food.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, Python, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Git

# TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Sweet Spot: Pastry E-Commerce - Live Preview | Github: Front End | Github: Back End

An e-commerce website for pastry chefs to sell their products to people in their communities.

- Implemented user interface employing React, Redux, and Thunk with Material UI for styling
- Incorporated Stripe API to create a fully functional customer checkout experience
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

# Pot n' Plot: Virtual Gardening — <u>Live Preview</u> | <u>Github</u>

A virtual gardening website for users to create a garden and populate it with real plant data.

- Built web app entirely with Ruby on Rails following the MVC structure and utilizing bcrypt for authentication
- Made use of Trefle.io API to create plant entries with real-time data

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer Intern

Dopple, San Francisco, CA

MAY 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop, design, and implement new and existing features for e-commerce platform using React.js
- Planned and integrated Instagram feed into homepage to allow for more interactive user experience and to increase customer retention
- Collaborate with the design and product teams to deliver top of the line visual experiences and engage in Agile Software Development team

#### Code Coach

#### theCoderSchool, Palo Alto, CA

MAY 2020 - PRESENT

- Tutor and teach students programming languages such as Python and Scratch using Zoom to hold online classes and meetings
- Encourage students to learn and understand different concepts together by applying what they learned to exercises and homework

# **Pastry Chef**

# Acrobat Outsourcing, San Francisco, CA

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2019

- Produced 500+ pastries, breads, and other desserts by 7pm deadline daily at in-house kitchen at Dropbox
- Mentored peers on standard pastry techniques and creation of gluten-, dairy-, and egg-free variations of a wide variety of products

# **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School - San Francisco, CA

OCTOBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Software Engineering Program - Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and Javascript

# City College of San Francisco — San Francisco, CA

AUGUST 2017 - JUNE 2018

Baking and Pastry Certification

# University of California, Riverside - Riverside, CA

SEPTEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2014

Bachelor of Science in Plant Biology